（ターニャ）晴れ 時々 砲弾日和
Clear, with a chance of artillery shells.
本日も視界良好につき―
Visibility is excellent again today,
and so a bloody war is taking place.
血で血を洗う激戦が
繰り広げられています
やっと協商連合が
片づいたと思ったら―
Just when you thought we'd finally
taken out the Entente Alliance,
おはようから おそようまで
砲弾と一緒の最前線勤務
you find yourself back to the front lines,
dealing with shells the whole day.
隣で寝ていた戦友が―
And sometimes, when you wake up,
朝 起きると死んでいることも
まれにある
you can find that the comrade who
went to sleep next to you is dead.
Unified Year 1925 April, Rhine Front
それが
ライン戦線の日常です
That's how life is on the Rhine Front.
（ターニャ）大隊各位 支援戦闘だ
Battalion, we'll provide
support for this mission.
Get in there as low as possible
可能なかぎり低空で突入し
敵砲兵を一気呵成(いっきかせい)にたたく
and take out all enemy artillery at once.
対空 対魔導は任意に行え
Deal with enemy air units
and mages as you see fit.
なお 我々の突入後も
友軍の砲撃は継続される
Also, our allies won't cease artillery fire
even after we begin the mission.
I doubt anyone in my battalion is stupid
enough to get hit by one of our shells,
味方の弾に当たる
マヌケなど―
Imperial Army 203rd Air Mage Battalion, Company 2
Second Lieutenant Warren Grantz
我が隊には
存在しないと思うが―
一応 留意せよ
but keep it in mind.
（グランツ）相変わらず盛大ですね
砲弾もタダじゃないというのに
They're as extravagant as ever.
Artillery shells aren't free, you know.
（ヴァイス）気を抜くなよ
曳下(えいか)砲撃用の時限信管だ
Stay sharp.
Those are airburst shells with timers.
Once they explode, their
fragments will rain down on us.
さく裂した破片が
雨のように降ってくるぞ
I know that.
分かってますよ
This is 05.
（ヴィーシャ）こちら05
I've sighted two enemy mage
companies approaching!
（ヴィーシャ）接近中の
２個魔導中隊を視認しました
Company 1, begin anti-mage combat.
（ターニャ）
第１中隊は対魔導師戦闘！
アポなしのマヌケどもを
たたき返せ！
Show these idiots we won't see them
without an appointment!
The rest of you, take out artillery.
残りは砲兵だ！
手早く済ませて合流せよ！
Do it fast, and rendezvous with us!
（ターニャ）
大隊諸君 にぎやかになってきたぞ
Battalion, it's getting lively here.
さぞかし楽しいだろう？
Fun, ain't it?
あっ… クッソ…
Damn it.
That's why I told you to stay sharp.
（ヴァイス）
だから気を抜くなと言ったんだ
First Lieutenant Weiss!
（グランツ）ヴァイス中尉殿…
But I managed to score a fair few points.
でも その分
スコアは稼げましたよ
Count on me next time, too.
次も期待しといてください
最後のスコアが
自爆になっても知らんぞ
Don't blame me if the last point
you score is when you get blown up.
Haven't had enough of
the commander up your ass?
まだ大隊長に
しごかれ足りないのか
I know...
分かってますよ
そこのセレブリャコーフ少尉を
見習え
Take a lesson from
Second Lieutenant Serebryakov.
She became a veteran just by
flying next to the battalion commander.
大隊長について飛ぶだけで
ベテランになったほどだ
んっ… 私が 何か？
What's this about me?
（ヴァイス）少尉は 大隊長殿と
ペアを組んで長いのだろう？
You and the commander have been
a pair for a long time, right?
（ヴィーシャ）ううっ…
まあ そうではありますが
Well, I suppose so, but...
隣を代わってくださりますか？
Will you take my place?
（ヴァイス）アッハハ…
軍務上 少尉と交代はできんよ
Military regulations won't allow that.
残念だが 一緒に飛ぶわけには…
I'm sorry, but we can't.
I see.
そうですか…
Major Degurechaff!
（情報将校）デグレチャフ少佐殿！
Is Major Degurechaff here?
（情報将校）デグレチャフ少佐殿は
おられますか？
次席指揮官の
ヴァイス中尉であります
I'm First Lieutenant Weiss,
her second-in-command.
緊急のご用件が？
Is this an emergency?
Episode Eight
Trial by Fire
後方地域が遮断された？
A rear area's been cut off?
（情報将校）は… はい
Y-Yes.
The partisans have started
a rebellion in Arene City.
アレーヌ市で
パルチザンの蜂起であります
（ターニャ）
アレーヌ市は元共和国領
Arene City was formerly Republican territory.
火種は くすぶっていたわけか…
We failed to extinguish
the opposition completely, huh?
Local garrison MPs failed to quell it.
（情報将校）憲兵隊からなる
駐屯部隊は鎮圧に失敗
既に鉄道を押さえられ―
They already control the railroad
and are straining our supply lines.
前線への補給路が
圧迫されているそうです
That's bad.
マズいな…
We have to fight without food or shells?
飯も砲弾もなしで
戦えと？
Imperial Territory Arene City
（民兵）死ね！
（民兵）この！
Die!
Take this!
Dog of the Empire!
（民兵）帝国の犬め！
A-An aerial insertion...
（憲兵）く… 空挺(くうてい)降下です
共和国軍が空挺作戦を
The Republic's begun an airship mission!
Enemy mages are trying to
hook up with the rebels—
敵魔導師が反徒と合流するもよ…
Republican Army 2nd Mage Company
Lieutenant Colonel Severin Bientot
Secure defensive points and
prepare for a long battle!
（ビアント）
橋頭保を確保し
長期戦に備えよ！
１日でも戦闘を長引かせ
帝国の首を絞め上げるぞ！
Every day that we can, we'll draw out
the war and strangle the enemy!
Rejoice, Major Degurechaff.
（ハンス）喜べ デグレチャフ少佐
Imperial Army Western Theater Command
Commander Mortiz Paul Von Han
（ハンス）本日14：23をもって
As of 1423 today, you have a special mission
from Theater Command.
方面軍司令部より
特命を発す
"The 203rd is to eliminate enemy mages
who have joined forces with Arene rebels.
“二〇三大隊は―”
“アレーヌ市の反徒と合流した
敵魔導部隊を速やかに排除”
Afterward, work with allies
to recapture the city."
“その後 友軍とともに
市街地の制圧に当たれ”
（ハンス）
事態は急を要する 任せたぞ
The situation requires quick action.
We're counting on you.
With pleasure, if those are your orders.
ご命令とあらば喜んで
But combat in a city will be difficult.
しかし 市街戦となると
手間取りそうですね
No need to worry about that.
（ハンス）その心配は要らん
（ターニャ）うん？
Strategic Command has given us a plan to
quickly eliminate enemy units in the city.
（ハンス）短時間で 市街地の
敵部隊を排除する一案が
参謀本部より提示された
（ターニャ）その案とは？
And what is it?
An evacuation order will be issued for Arene.
これより アレーヌ市に
避難勧告が出される
Under international law, anyone who
remains in the city after that order
勧告以降 市内に残っている者は
国際法的に―
全て共和国軍部隊と
見なされるだろう
will be considered a Republican soldier.
Orders from above are to
eliminate all hostiles in the city.
上からは 市内に残った敵全てを
排除しろとの命令だ
Once you wipe out the enemy mages,
our artillery will begin a barrage.
敵魔導部隊を排除後
砲兵隊による砲撃を行う
（ターニャ）なるほど
I see.
我々は 行くも地獄
So we've got hell ahead of us,
and hell behind us.
引くも地獄というわけですか
Naturally, this is a very silly question.
（ターニャ）
ところで たあいのない
さえずりでしょうが―
But our enemy is only
the Republican Army, yes?
我々の敵は あくまでも
共和国軍なのですね？
（ハンス）当たり前ではないか
Of course.
If possible, I would like to know
the nature of these enemy combatants.
（ターニャ）できれば
予想される敵戦力の構成を―
ご教示いただきたいのですが
（ハンス）少数の
共和国軍魔導師以外は民兵だ
All of them, except a small number
of Republican mages, are militiamen.
Many Imperial civilians have
already been captured.
既に多くの帝国国民が
捕虜となっている
（ターニャ）
それは なんとも痛ましい
How sad...
We must get to work immediately, then.
直ちに行動を
開始せねばなりませんな
Yes.
Well, the civilian presence will be an issue.
まあ 民間人がいれば
制約にもなりましょうが
まさか敵の正規軍が 人間の盾を
使うはずもありませんしね
But I can't see regular soldiers
using civilians as human shields.
We're simply taking out an enemy base...
我々は共和国軍の拠点を
たたくのみ
ルールにのっとって
勧告を行う以上は―
Since we'll be following the rules
and issuing an evacuation order—
心おきなく…
（ハンス）少佐
Major?
失礼しました
I'm sorry, sir.
しかし 残念なことだ…
It is a sad thing, though.
Yeah, it's terribly sad.
（ターニャ）ええ 本当に残念で
しかたがありません
ですが 我らは軍人
But we are soldiers,
命令とあらば麗しのアレーヌとて
焼かねばなりません
and if orders say we must burn
beautiful Arene to the ground,
that is what we must do.
Who would want to be a soldier, huh?
（ハンス）
軍人になど なるものではないな
（民兵）
フンッ 何が避難勧告だ くっ！
An evacuation order? Ha!
Battalion members,
it's time for a sightseeing trip.
大隊諸君 観光旅行だ
The enemy has sent airships.
敵の空挺だ 魔導部隊が
アレーヌ市の民兵と合流したらしい
Their mages have joined up
with the Arene militia.
The city has fallen into Republican hands.
同市は今や共和国軍の手に落ちた
Of course, we'll take it back!
当然 奪還する！
さて それにあたり難題がある
But there's a problem.
We must eliminate
all Republican forces in the city.
我らは 市内の共和国軍を全て
排除しなければならない
All?
（ターニャ）当然ではあるが
非戦闘員への発砲は厳しく禁じる
Well, firing on non-combatants
is strictly forbidden.
But since we're fighting in a city,
ただし 市街戦につき―
物的破損については
破壊許可が出ている
we have permission to destroy property.
Additionally, we'll issue declarations before
and after combat with enemy mages.
なお 敵魔導師交戦前と排除後に
それぞれ勧告を行う
If the enemy accepts our terms
of surrender, then very well.
敵が降伏勧告を受諾すればよし
If they don't, we wipe them out.
そうでない場合は
掃討戦に移行する 以上だ
Dismissed.
（隊員）掃討戦？
（隊員）市街地でか…
Wipe them out?
In a city?
（隊員）敵を全て排除って…
（隊員）まさか…
Eliminate all enemies?
She can't mean...
（グランツ）
本当にいいんでしょうか？
Is this really okay?
Wiping out all enemies in the city means...
市内の敵全てを
排除するってことは つまり…
It means...
I can't imagine them surrendering
just because we issue a declaration.
勧告を行ったところで
素直に応じるとは思えませんし
And I heard we're even using
an artillery barrage.
聞くところでは 砲撃まで行うと…
Besides, differentiating between
militia and non-combatants is impossible!
だいたい 民兵と非戦闘員の
区別など不可能です
We might end up—
下手すれば 虐…
それ以上は言うな
Don't say another word.
Get in here and stay put!
（民兵）
こっちだ！ おとなしくしろ！
（ビアント）
わずか数時間で飛んでくるとは…
I didn't expect them to be
here in just a few hours.
よほど事態を
深刻に受け止めているらしいな
It seems they're taking this seriously.
Bravo Leader to Combat Area Control.
（共和国魔導師）
ブラボーリーダーより戦域管制
Sending data on enemy mage unit.
敵魔導部隊のデータを送信する
確認せよ
Confirm.
The Devil of the Rhine?
（ビアント）
“ラインの悪魔”だと？
連中 大物を引っ張り出してきたな
They brought out the big guns, huh?
Enemy vanguard has passed
the IFF boundary.
（共和国魔導師）
敵先鋒(せんぽう) 防空識別圏突破
市外上空へ 急速接近中
Approaching airspace above
the city at high speed.
They're coming!
来るぞ！ 長距離伏撃戦 用意！
Prepare for long-distance ambush!
（グランツ）誰もいないですね…
No one's here, huh?
An evacuation order was issued.
（ヴァイス）避難勧告が
発令されたのだ 当然だろう
So of course not.
Ambushers! We're being sniped at!
伏兵！ 狙撃されています！
チッ… エンゲージ！ 各員散開！
Engage!
Everyone, split up!
Enemy locations confirmed.
敵位置を捕捉！
４時方向および７時方向の尖塔(せんとう)！
Four o'clock and seven o'clock.
（ターニャ）
チッ 素早い… 逃がすか！
They're fast.
You won't escape!
Damn it.
クソッ どこだ!? うっ…
Where are they?
Everyone, prepare for close-range combat.
（ターニャ）各自 近接戦の用意！
ヤツらの狙いは時間稼ぎだ！
Their goal is to buy time!
Don't get scared!
（ターニャ）ひるむな！
（隊員たち）はっ！
Yes, ma'am!
Second Lieutenant Grantz...
グランツ少尉
すまないが 妙に疲れた
Sorry, but I'm feeling strangely tired.
強壮剤をもらえないか
（グランツ）あっ はい
Can I get a stimulant?
R-Right!
First Lieutenant Weiss! You've been hit!
ヴァイス中尉殿 被弾されています
（ヴァイス）何!?
What?
気づいていないのですか？
止血帯を… 早く！
You didn't notice?
I'll use a coagulant.
Hurry!
Second Lieutenant,
how does that idiot look?
（ターニャ）
少尉 マヌケの容体は？
His life isn't in danger,
but I don't think he can keep fighting.
（グランツ）命に差し障りは
ありませんが 継戦は困難かと
Fine.
（ターニャ）やむをえん…
ヴァイス中尉 さっさと下がれ
First Lieutenant Weiss, get out of here.
あ… しかし大隊長殿！
But, Battalion Commander—
（ターニャ）貴様１人
抜けたところで問題はない
Your leaving won't create problems.
足手まといになるくらいなら
被弾した連中をまとめて帰還しろ
I'd rather you take all the wounded
out of here than slow us down.
はい…
Yes, ma'am.
First Lieutenant Koenig will
take over as second-in-command.
（ターニャ）次席指揮権は
ケーニッヒ中尉に継承
第２中隊の指揮は私が執る
I'll take command of Company 2.
Roger.
了解です… ご武運を
Good luck.
貴様は考えすぎるのだ
You think too much.
You hesitated, didn't you?
躊躇(ちゅうちょ)したのだろう？
この大バカ者め！
You fool!
Be prepared for the worst when I get back.
帰ったら覚悟しておけ！
すまん…
I'm sorry.
Enemy mages have scattered!
（共和国魔導師）敵魔導師 散開
（共和国魔導師）突っ込んできます
They're charging us!
チッ… 下がるぞ！
距離をとって撃ち続けろ！
Fall back!
Stay at range and keep firing!
Enemy mages are retreating.
（ヴィーシャ）敵魔導師が後退中！
建物内に引きこもるようです
They're hiding inside a building.
（ターニャ）
しかたない 突入は中止だ！
Fine, the assault is canceled.
そのまま押し込んどけ
Let them go inside.
Are you sure?
よろしいのですか？
（ターニャ）市街地外部の砲兵隊に
手出しできなくすれば―
If we ensure they can't touch
the artillery units outside the city,
目的は達成されたも同然
we've basically achieved our objective.
What happens later isn't our problem.
そのあとのことまでは
あずかり知らんよ
Roger.
分かりました
Let's send our message.
では 呼びかけるとしよう
砲兵隊にもつなげ
Connect me to artillery, too.
A message to the irregulars
engaged in armed rebellion.
（ターニャ）武装蜂起せりし
非正規戦闘要員に勧告す
In accordance with Article 26, Clause 3
of the Wartime Combat Treaty,
戦時陸戦規定
第26条３項に基づき―
we request the release of
all Imperial civilians in your custody.
帝国臣民の解放を要求する
諸君が不当にも捕虜とせりし
アレーヌ市民を解放せよ
Release the people of Arene
that you have unlawfully imprisoned.
（民兵）ふざけるな！
Shut up!
（民兵）
我らこそ正当なアレーヌ市民だ！
We are the people of Arene!
（民兵）
不当な捕虜など存在しない！
There are no unlawful prisoners!
諸君らの虐殺行為は許容できない
We cannot allow your massacres to continue.
In accordance with Article 8, Clause 5
of the Wartime Combat Treaty,
戦時陸戦規定 第８条５項により
担当官を接見させよ
send us your commanding officer.
勧告を受け入れぬ場合
必然的に戦闘員と見なす
If you fail to heed this warning,
we will be forced to consider you combatants.
It's way too late for that.
何を今更！
（民兵）
チクショウ！ 帝国のクソどもめ！
Damn those Imperial shits!
What do we do? What do we do?
どうする？ どうする！
Damn it... Damn it all!
（民兵）
チクショウ… チクショウ！
（民兵たち）おい…
Did you get that?
（ターニャ）観測は？
Yes.
（ヴィーシャ）
はい 映像を宝珠に記録しました
I recorded it with my computation jewel.
（ターニャ）司令部へ送信しろ
Send it to Command.
Sheesh... This is the problem with militias
that don't have a chain of command.
まったく… 統制のとれていない
民兵というのは これだから
Command to all units involved
with the operation.
（通信兵）
司令部より 作戦参加の全部隊へ
We will move to wipe out the enemy.
これより掃討戦へ移行する
アレーヌ市内の共和国軍を排除せよ
Eliminate Republican forces in Arene.
さて 降伏勧告の義務は果たした
Okay, I've fulfilled my duty by
demanding their surrender.
Let's get to work... "protecting our people."
我々は自国民保護のための
任務に―
当たるとしよう
Wha...
What is this?
何なのだ…
What the hell is this?!
何なのだ これは！
Commander Bientot!
（共和国魔導師）ビアント隊長！
ぐっ… 共和国市民を保護しつつ
戦域から撤退する 急げ！
Protect the Republican citizens
and withdraw from the combat zone!
Hurry!
Loading complete.
（帝国兵士）装填(そうてん)完了！
Fire.
（帝国兵士）撃て
This way!
（隊員）こっちだー！
（隊員）しっかりしろー！
Hang in there!
ハァッ ハァッ…
自分は… 捕虜の救出を…
I'm just saving the prisoners...
I'm just helping people.
人助けをしているだけだ…
Anyone else?
（ヴィーシャ）残りは？
（隊員）これで全員かと
I think this is everyone.
Attention, Pixie Battalion.
（通信兵）ピクシー大隊へ通達
現在Ｂ４地点にて―
Remaining enemy mages are at point B4, serving as a rear guard.
後退中の敵残存魔導師が
殿軍を務めている
They're interfering with our spotters
and preventing our artillery from firing.
友軍の観測班が妨害され
砲撃が行えない 排除は可能か？
Can you take them out?
I have visual.
（ターニャ）
目視した 問題ない 可能だ
No problem.
It's possible.
As soon as the rear guard is down,
（通信兵）殿軍を排除後
砲撃を再開する ５分以内に願う
we'll resume the artillery attack.
Try to finish within five minutes.
（ターニャ）
任務了解 最善を尽くす
Roger that.
I'll do my best.
ハァ…
（着地音）
（グランツ）大隊長殿！
Battalion Commander!
Please reconsider...
どうか ご再考を！
か… 彼らは 砲撃から
逃げるすべなど知りません！
They don't know how to
escape an artillery barrage!
もし… もし我々が
あの魔導師たちを排除したら…
If... If we take out those mages—
（ターニャ）帝国の敵が
砲撃で吹き飛ぶのだろうな
The Empire's enemies will be
wiped out by artillery.
結構なことだ
Fine by me.
（グランツ）しかし それは！
（ターニャ）グランツ少尉
But that's—
Second Lieutenant Grantz,
the enemy you let go will
take up his gun again.
逃した敵は また銃を取るのだ
To shoot us.
我々を撃つためにな
ヤツらを逃せば
If we let them go, some will become
new soldiers who hate the Empire.
あの中から 帝国に憎悪を燃やす
新兵が生まれるだろう
So... You want us to kill them
just for that reason?!
だから… だから殺せと!?
うっ… ぐわっ！
This is the order from our superiors.
（ターニャ）これは上からの命令だ
敵は撃たねば撃たれるのだ
We shoot the enemy, or they'll shoot us.
少なくとも“撃つな”と
言われるまでは撃たねばならん
If nothing else, we must shoot
until we're told not to anymore.
I'll pretend I didn't hear what you just said.
（ターニャ）先ほどまでの言葉は
聞かなかったことにしてやろう
But I'll say this once more.
もう一度だけ言う
これは上からの命令だ
This is the order from our superiors.
Take up your gun.
銃を… 取りたまえ
What did you want to discuss?
（ゼートゥーア）話というのは？
（レルゲン）昨年夏 軍大学の
第17研究所に提出された論文です
This paper,
which was submitted last summer
to the Army Academy's 17th Lab.
The paper deals with ways to
legalize combat in cities.
論文の要旨は―
“いかにして市街戦そのものを
合法化するか”について―
It contains a way to interpret wartime law,
国際法を解釈し直すことで―
都市砲撃の制限を回避する旨が
記されています
to avoid the restrictions on
artillery bombardment of cities.
Did you use this when you
planned this operation?
閣下は これを参考に今回の作戦を
立案されたのでしょうか？
If I did?
（ゼートゥーア）だとしたら？
Nothing.
何も…
I just wanted to know for certain.
ただ 小官は…
確認したかっただけであります
The author of the paper was
Major Degurechaff, wasn't it?
論文の執筆者は…
デグレチャフ少佐なのですね
As you say, she seems to be
an extremely talented soldier.
（ゼートゥーア）貴官の言うとおり
少佐は極めて優れた軍人のようだ
Not using those talents would be foolish.
あれほどの優秀な人材を
活用しない手はない
I am going to give her an
extremely important job
デグレチャフ少佐に
共和国との戦争終結に向けての
大役を任せる
to end the war with the Republic.
（ドレイク）
ようやく意識が戻りましたか
You're finally awake?
Allied Kingdom Humanitarian Aid Group "Peace World Hospital"
I'm told you were found floating
in a fjord, critically wounded.
重傷を負ってフィヨルドに
浮いているところを―
救出されたそうです
You've been unconscious for months.
何か月も意識不明で―
They only identified you a few days ago.
身元が判明したのも 数日前と
（アンソン）光を… 見た
I saw a light.
あれは… 神の光だ
The light of God...
Very interesting.
なかなか興味深いですね
それで 神様は何と？
And what did God tell you?
To destroy that devil.
（アンソン）
あの悪魔を… 討ち滅ぼせと
Next Episode
Prepare to Advance